<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_us"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://clickfortech.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://clickfortech.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_us" /><updated>2022-02-05T17:22:18+00:00</updated><id>https://clickfortech.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Click For Tech</title><subtitle>Latest and trending technology topics are published here.</subtitle><author><name>Ashok</name></author><entry><title type="html">Elon Musk Private Jet Tracker</title><link href="https://clickfortech.com/internet/Elon-Musk-Private-Jet-Tracker/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elon Musk Private Jet Tracker" /><published>2022-02-05T04:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-05T04:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://clickfortech.com/internet/Elon-Musk-Private-Jet-Tracker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clickfortech.com/internet/Elon-Musk-Private-Jet-Tracker/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JxckSweeney&quot;&gt;Jack Sweeney&lt;/a&gt;, a 19 year old college student made a deal of $5000 with Elon Musk for shutting down his twitter account &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ElonJet&quot;&gt;@ElonJet&lt;/a&gt; which automatically tweets the location details of Elon’s private jet. He wrote a software program to parse the data, publicly available about the flying path of all the flights in ADS-B Exchange. Sweeney uses the flight’s latitude to determine whether the flight has landed or not. But it doesn’t show any information about future paths of the flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker/elonjet.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Sweeney created 15 such auto-bot twitter handles to auto-tweet 15 different celebrity’s private jet paths. Elon Musk felt this could be a security risk, so he contacted Jack Sweeney to shut this down. During the conversation Must asked about how much money Sweeney made using that account. Sweeney replied as $20. And Elon Musk proposed an offer to the college going teenager of USD 5000 to shut this down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok</name></author><category term="Internet" /><summary type="html">Jack Sweeney, a 19 year old college student made a deal of $5000 with Elon Musk for shutting down his twitter account @ElonJet which automatically tweets the location details of Elon’s private jet. He wrote a software program to parse the data, publicly available about the flying path of all the flights in ADS-B Exchange. Sweeney uses the flight’s latitude to determine whether the flight has landed or not. But it doesn’t show any information about future paths of the flights.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker/elon-musk-private-jet-tracker.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CES 2022 New launches for Laptop users</title><link href="https://clickfortech.com/consumerelectronics/CES-2022-New-launches-for-Laptop-users/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CES 2022 New launches for Laptop users" /><published>2022-01-09T05:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T05:15:00+00:00</updated><id>https://clickfortech.com/consumerelectronics/CES-2022-New-launches-for-Laptop-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clickfortech.com/consumerelectronics/CES-2022-New-launches-for-Laptop-users/">&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of joyful news from CES 2022 for Laptop users. New Ultra
Portable and Gaming laptops launched in CES 2022 are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dell-xps-13-plus&quot;&gt;Dell XPS 13 Plus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/Dell-XPS-13-Plus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dell XPS 13 Plus launched with a flat touchpad and palm resting place below the
keyboard. There is no physical division on the sides of the touchpad. So the
portion below the keyboard looks like a flat bar. Dell calls it as a “Haptic
ForcePad”. When a click happens on it, there is no physical depress happens,
instead it reproduces a sensation of depressing. But for initial days it would
be a little hard to identify the edges of the touchpad, but after a while of
usage it would be easier. This design of the touchpad looks stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dell replaces the physical function keys row with a capacitive touch. These are
just a little LED buttons on a flat bar. And the keyboard is edge to edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flat Function key row, edge to edge keyboard and a flat bar for palm rest with
touchpad makes this edition of XPS 13 one of the best in look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XPS 13 Plus is powered by 12th Gen Intel processors. And the display will be
available on both FHD and OLED 4K. Along with this the regular Dell XPS 13 with
regular keyboard and touchpad also would be available this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hp-elite-dragonfly-g3-and-hp-elite-dragonfly-chromebook&quot;&gt;HP Elite Dragonfly G3 and HP Elite Dragonfly Chromebook.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/HP-Elite-Dragonfly-G3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dragonfly G3 has a change in aspect ratio compared to its predecessor Dragonfly
G2; it is now with a 3:2 display rather than 16:9. Good for a Creative
Professional and general user, but bad for a Software Programmer. G2 was a
2-in-1 type, but the G3 is not a 2-in-1. It comes with 12th Gen Intel processors
with vPro support. Storage and memory options are available upto 2TB and 32GB.
It comes with a 68Wh battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dragonfly Chromebook laptop is the first Chromebook in this lineup, comes
with a haptic trackpad, a Sure View Reflect privacy screen (prevents sensitive
information visible on the computer screen for the onlookers from the sides)
and a fingerprint sensor. Storage and memory options are available upto 512GB
and 32GB. It comes with a 51Whr battery. It might come with an inexpensive
pricing tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the Dragonfly laptops will be available in March/April. Pricings are not
revealed, but it is not going to be cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;asus-rog-flow-z13&quot;&gt;Asus ROG Flow Z13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/Asus-ROG-Flow-Z13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asus launched a powerful detachable 2 in 1 laptop called Asus ROG Flow Z13. It
managed to stuff in a RTX 3050 Ti to that detachable display unit. So
technically a powerful tablet. Even it supports an external GPU. It weighs 2.43
pounds and 0.47 inch in thickness. It runs Core i9 12900H and its storage and
memory are available upto 1TB and 16GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;asus-zenbook-14-oled-space-edition&quot;&gt;Asus Zenbook 14 OLED Space Edition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/Asus-14-OLED-Space-Edition.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Asus launched a new notebook in the Zenbook series called Zenbook 14 OLED Space
edition. Asus claims that it complies with the US Space System Command Standard
and it can operate in extreme climates. It has a tiny 3.5 inch OLED display on
the lid and it displays various animations. When the laptop is closed, this tiny
screen displays date, time and battery capacity. Apart from that it is a 14 inch
notebook with 16:10 OLED touch screen with a 90Hz refresh rate. It is powered by
12th Gen Intel H series processors. Storage and memory options are available
upto 1TB and 32GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tcl-book-14-go&quot;&gt;TCL Book 14 Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/tcl-book-14-go.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCL launched the Book 14 Go, it is an entry level laptop for lite users. It is
powered by the Snapdragon 7c ARM processor. Pricing starts at $349.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amd-ryzen-6000-6nm-laptop-processors&quot;&gt;AMD Ryzen 6000 6nm Laptop Processors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMD showcased its new 6000 series of Laptop processors built on Zen 3 Plus
architecture in a 6nm form factor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok</name></author><category term="ConsumerElectronics" /><summary type="html">There is a lot of joyful news from CES 2022 for Laptop users. New Ultra Portable and Gaming laptops launched in CES 2022 are listed below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/ces-2022-laptops.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/ces-2022-laptops/ces-2022-laptops.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CES 2022 New launches for Desktop users</title><link href="https://clickfortech.com/consumerelectronics/CES-2022-New-launches-for-Desktop-users/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CES 2022 New launches for Desktop users" /><published>2022-01-09T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://clickfortech.com/consumerelectronics/CES-2022-New-launches-for-Desktop-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clickfortech.com/consumerelectronics/CES-2022-New-launches-for-Desktop-users/">&lt;p&gt;New launches in CES 2022 which addresses the expectations of Desktop users
are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;razer-sophia&quot;&gt;Razer Sophia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/ces-2022-desktops/razer-sophia-modular-desk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Razer introduces a prototype of a Modular Table Computer called Razer Sophia.
It is a table with four legs and on top of that there is a modular slot for
building a high performant PC. And a 65 inch or 75 inch display is attached to
it. So it is a table with an attached computer and monitor. What a fantastic
concept for a PC enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This module table has 13 swappable module slots for plug and play PC components.
These modules can be a secondary screen, PC temperature monitors, calendar
displays, wireless Qi chargers, a mug heater, pen tablets, audio mixers, CPU and
GPU monitors and much more. This modular nature helps users to customize based
on their needs. This reminds me of Google’s failure project Modular Smartphone
Ara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intel-core-i9-12900ks&quot;&gt;Intel Core i9 12900KS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel has launched the Core i9 12900KS processor at CES 2022, which can run on
5.5 GHz clock speed on a single core. And it can run on 5.2 GHz clock speed on
all cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amd-5nm-ryzen-7000-desktop-processors&quot;&gt;AMD 5nm Ryzen 7000 Desktop Processors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMD showcased 5nm Ryzen 7000 Desktop processors with Zen 4 architecture, and it
will be available in the second half of 2022. This will be using the new AM5
socket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this AMD showcased an upgraded version of its Ryzen 5000 line up
processor, called Ryzen 7 5800X3D. It is using 3D V-Cache technology. It is a
7nm node with AM4 socket support.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok</name></author><category term="ConsumerElectronics" /><summary type="html">New launches in CES 2022 which addresses the expectations of Desktop users are listed below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/ces-2022-desktops/ces-2022-desktops.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/ces-2022-desktops/ces-2022-desktops.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Non Fungible Token</title><link href="https://clickfortech.com/dapps/Non-Fungible-Token/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Non Fungible Token" /><published>2022-01-07T04:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T04:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://clickfortech.com/dapps/Non-Fungible-Token</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clickfortech.com/dapps/Non-Fungible-Token/">&lt;p&gt;Non Fungible Tokens (NFT) is a kind of application that runs over Blockchain
technology. Non Fungible means something unique which cannot be replaced with
something else. Cryptocurrencies are Fungible tokens. Non Fungible Token
represents a unique piece of digital art such as digital picture, music or
video. These digital pictures can be either shot using a camera or created
artistically using Software. When someone creates a unique digital content, he
can create a NFT for it by adding that content file to a blockchain, which
cannot be copied, edited or deleted. And it can be sold to the interested
buyers. NFT is an evolution of the fine art auction system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/nft/nft.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;popular-nfts&quot;&gt;Popular NFTs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Non Fungible Tokens have been there since 2015, but in 2021 it is getting
more popular. “Everydays: The First 5000 days” is a collage of 5000 digital
images created by Mike Winkelmann, and it gets sold as NFT for $60 million in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Winkelmann becomes the living expensive art creator, and he is also
called as Beeple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nike Patented a concept of creating a unique NFT token on blockchain for every
pair of Nike shoes it sells, named as CryptoKicks. Buyer holds both a physical
shoe and a corresponding NFT, by which the buyer can verify the authenticity of
the shoe. When the shoe gets resold to someone else, ownership can be
transferred for both physical shoe and corresponding digital NFT token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CryptoKitties runs on Ethereum block chain platform is a well popular NFT on
which virtual kittens are sold. Another surprisingly popular NFTs are the grey
colour rock image on the etherrock platform. Yes, just a grey colored rock
images are getting sold for a million dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2022/nft/popular-nft.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makersplace, opensea, rarible and Nifty gateway are the few places where NFTs
are exchanged, but there are plenty of other places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunities-in-nft&quot;&gt;Opportunities in NFT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this booming NFT community, there is a good opportunity for two sets of
people to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-digital-artist&quot;&gt;An Digital artist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist who makes digital images or stickers, then you should
utilize the NFT platform to sell your art. Even the NFT platforms allows to
enable a share when the art gets resold to a new buyer. So by this way the
creator gets a share when the value of art appreciates in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-art-buyer&quot;&gt;An Art buyer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a digital art buyer, you can buy the digital art as NFTs and keep
it as a collection. Even you can make a profit by reselling it after the value
gets appreciated in future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok</name></author><category term="DApps" /><category term="DApps" /><summary type="html">Non Fungible Tokens (NFT) is a kind of application that runs over Blockchain technology. Non Fungible means something unique which cannot be replaced with something else. Cryptocurrencies are Fungible tokens. Non Fungible Token represents a unique piece of digital art such as digital picture, music or video. These digital pictures can be either shot using a camera or created artistically using Software. When someone creates a unique digital content, he can create a NFT for it by adding that content file to a blockchain, which cannot be copied, edited or deleted. And it can be sold to the interested buyers. NFT is an evolution of the fine art auction system.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/nft/non-fungible-token.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2022/nft/non-fungible-token.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Internet Web 3.0</title><link href="https://clickfortech.com/internet/Internet-Web-3.0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Internet Web 3.0" /><published>2021-12-19T04:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T04:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://clickfortech.com/internet/Internet-Web-3.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clickfortech.com/internet/Internet-Web-3.0/">&lt;p&gt;Internet technology is one of the key inventions from the 20th century. It
was introduced in the year 1990 and it evolved into 3 generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web 1.0 is the period between 1990 and 2005.
Web 2.0 started in 2005 and continuing till date.
Web 3.0 starts now with the new technology called Decentralized Applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2021/web3.0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-10&quot;&gt;Web 1.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In initial period of web 1.0, Internet was used to host Static file contents in
the form of HTML files.  Mainly used for hosting documentation and blog. User
can use a personal computer to access the webserver using the browser
application. Netscafe Navigator and Internet Explorer are the browsers used at
that period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with static services, an user interactive dynamic services was also
introduced later in mid 90s over Internet. For example eMail and chat services
was introduced by Yahoo, Hotmail, AOL. Government was started providing online
services for their citizens. Major banks was also started providing online
banking services, in which user can view transactions and make online money
transfer by just sitting in front of a Personal computer. Academic institutes
was started providing registration services for academic courses over Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-20&quot;&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Web 2.0 period, lot of new user equipments has been launched with
Internet accessing capability. For example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart phones was launched, by which user can access the Internet services
on-the-go. And thanks to evolution on Telecom services during this period,
by which 3G and 4G launched all over the world. Which gives better Internet
services for the users who are in transit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2021/web1.0-and-web2.0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next a wearables got introduced, which is more than a wrist watch. It can
track our health conditions like heart rate, O2 levels and our physical
activities and update to the connected smartphone. And lot of Smartphone apps
can push short notifications and information to it. Some of the wearables can
accept SIM card as well by which we can make calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IoT Device got launched, lot of home devices like Camera, Washing machine,
refrigerator, light can connect to the Internet via Home wifi,
by which user can control or monitor these devices far away from home.
Even in Industries also IoT devices started getting used to track and control
manufacturing units with less Human resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the changes happened on the front end side. Lot of new services
gets introduced in back end as well. For example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media services gets introduced like Facebook, Insta, Whatsapp, Youtube,
Telegram. By which users were able to communicate with peoples around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video On Demand services like Netflix, Amazon Prime etc started in this period,
by which user can stream Video content to their devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computing and Storage resources has been provided as service from Internet by
big players like Google, AWS, Azure. By which user can easily access computing
resources and pay as they use. With the help of this cloud resources, Internet
based Business service providers (like cab hailing service, delivery service)
can start their business by using Cloud resources initialy, without investing
heavily on the On-premise data centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting changes in this period is Edge computing, which are very
similar to Cloud servers, but sits close to the user on the ISP premise, to
serve the user request with much lesser latency. Lot of VoD and social media
services, has leveraged these edge technology to provide better Quality of
service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-30&quot;&gt;Web 3.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In web 3.0 era, Decentralization technology is going to be used to build
services for user without any trusted entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the Internet services so far we have seen in Web 1.0 and Web 2.0 are
provided by a server from a public or private organization. These services are
centralized applications. If tomorrow any one of those organization decides
to stop the service, then it is a huge setback for users. That is the
important problem in Centralized applications in Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/2021/web3.0-decentralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In decentralized technology each user forms a network, for communication or
data operation, in which there is no governing entity. Each user validates all
other’s operation or communication. And each user holds the complete set of
data, so no need of a Centralized data center to store data or computation.
So this decetranlized technology is going to remove centralized server, which
is getting deployed and operated by a single party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application runs on Decentralized technology is called DApps (Decentralized
Applications). It runs on network of computers using peer-to-peer technology, instead of running on a single server. It uses a Smart Contracts to complete
the transaction between two entity without the need for third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advantages-of-dapps&quot;&gt;Advantages of DApps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No need of a trusted third party for authenticating the desired operation.
Each user gets a copy of the complete data in the form of a distributed ledger,
and it can be verified with less computing power. If a user modified the ledger,
it will not get accepted by all the other users in the network.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no single entity who handles all the task. Because of this there
is no single point of failure. In centralized application, there is a high
chance of no service or poor service incase of failure or exhaustion on the
server. Even recently facebook and youtube was not accessible for certain
duration due to technical glitch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disadvantages-of-dapps&quot;&gt;Disadvantages of DApps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First disadvantage is limitation on scaling. If the data becomes much larger
it would be hard for all nodes to store and process it. So scaling would be
challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After deployment, Software code of DApps will be hard to modify for bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet technologies is the back bone of rapid evolution of Human life in the
last three decade. With the new addition of Decentralized Technology to
Internet is going to make an another rapid evolution to Human life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok</name></author><category term="Internet" /><category term="Internet" /><summary type="html">Internet technology is one of the key inventions from the 20th century. It was introduced in the year 1990 and it evolved into 3 generations. Web 1.0 is the period between 1990 and 2005. Web 2.0 started in 2005 and continuing till date. Web 3.0 starts now with the new technology called Decentralized Applications. Web 1.0 In initial period of web 1.0, Internet was used to host Static file contents in the form of HTML files. Mainly used for hosting documentation and blog. User can use a personal computer to access the webserver using the browser application. Netscafe Navigator and Internet Explorer are the browsers used at that period. Along with static services, an user interactive dynamic services was also introduced later in mid 90s over Internet. For example eMail and chat services was introduced by Yahoo, Hotmail, AOL. Government was started providing online services for their citizens. Major banks was also started providing online banking services, in which user can view transactions and make online money transfer by just sitting in front of a Personal computer. Academic institutes was started providing registration services for academic courses over Internet. Web 2.0 During Web 2.0 period, lot of new user equipments has been launched with Internet accessing capability. For example Smart phones was launched, by which user can access the Internet services on-the-go. And thanks to evolution on Telecom services during this period, by which 3G and 4G launched all over the world. Which gives better Internet services for the users who are in transit. Next a wearables got introduced, which is more than a wrist watch. It can track our health conditions like heart rate, O2 levels and our physical activities and update to the connected smartphone. And lot of Smartphone apps can push short notifications and information to it. Some of the wearables can accept SIM card as well by which we can make calls. IoT Device got launched, lot of home devices like Camera, Washing machine, refrigerator, light can connect to the Internet via Home wifi, by which user can control or monitor these devices far away from home. Even in Industries also IoT devices started getting used to track and control manufacturing units with less Human resources. These are the changes happened on the front end side. Lot of new services gets introduced in back end as well. For example Social media services gets introduced like Facebook, Insta, Whatsapp, Youtube, Telegram. By which users were able to communicate with peoples around the globe. Video On Demand services like Netflix, Amazon Prime etc started in this period, by which user can stream Video content to their devices. Computing and Storage resources has been provided as service from Internet by big players like Google, AWS, Azure. By which user can easily access computing resources and pay as they use. With the help of this cloud resources, Internet based Business service providers (like cab hailing service, delivery service) can start their business by using Cloud resources initialy, without investing heavily on the On-premise data centers. Another interesting changes in this period is Edge computing, which are very similar to Cloud servers, but sits close to the user on the ISP premise, to serve the user request with much lesser latency. Lot of VoD and social media services, has leveraged these edge technology to provide better Quality of service. Web 3.0 In web 3.0 era, Decentralization technology is going to be used to build services for user without any trusted entity. All the Internet services so far we have seen in Web 1.0 and Web 2.0 are provided by a server from a public or private organization. These services are centralized applications. If tomorrow any one of those organization decides to stop the service, then it is a huge setback for users. That is the important problem in Centralized applications in Internet. In decentralized technology each user forms a network, for communication or data operation, in which there is no governing entity. Each user validates all other’s operation or communication. And each user holds the complete set of data, so no need of a Centralized data center to store data or computation. So this decetranlized technology is going to remove centralized server, which is getting deployed and operated by a single party. Application runs on Decentralized technology is called DApps (Decentralized Applications). It runs on network of computers using peer-to-peer technology, instead of running on a single server. It uses a Smart Contracts to complete the transaction between two entity without the need for third party. Advantages of DApps No need of a trusted third party for authenticating the desired operation. Each user gets a copy of the complete data in the form of a distributed ledger, and it can be verified with less computing power. If a user modified the ledger, it will not get accepted by all the other users in the network. There is no single entity who handles all the task. Because of this there is no single point of failure. In centralized application, there is a high chance of no service or poor service incase of failure or exhaustion on the server. Even recently facebook and youtube was not accessible for certain duration due to technical glitch. Disadvantages of DApps First disadvantage is limitation on scaling. If the data becomes much larger it would be hard for all nodes to store and process it. So scaling would be challenging. After deployment, Software code of DApps will be hard to modify for bug fixes. Conclusion Internet technologies is the back bone of rapid evolution of Human life in the last three decade. With the new addition of Decentralized Technology to Internet is going to make an another rapid evolution to Human life.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2021/web3.0.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://clickfortech.com/assets/images/2021/web3.0.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>